# **JORGE RODRÍGUEZ DÍAZ**

# Senior Software Engineer

☑ jrodriguezdiazz@outlook.com ♀ Espaillat, Dom. Rep. in @jrodriguezdiazz ♠ @jrodriguezdiazz

## **₽** PROFILE

Jorge is an experienced software engineer with 4 years of industry experience developing web applications. His strong technical skills include expertise in modern web technologies such as React, NodeJS, TypeScript, HTML, CSS, and SQL. He's a team player who is eager to learn and always willing to help others.

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

**EPAM Systems**  $\mathscr{D}$ 

May 2022 - Present | Remote

Senior Software Engineer

Client: Dow Jones ℰ

#### **Description:**

- · Successfully implemented lazy loading technology for ads, significantly increasing ad viewability and engagement, and improving CPM (Cost Per Thousand Impressions).
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams including developers, product managers, and third-party vendors to ensure a seamless transition to the new ad-serving mechanism (Ad Browser Configuration Tool (ABT)), minimizing disruption to the website's revenue stream.

Newtech S.R.L. *⊘* 

Aug 2021 – May 2022 | Remote

Software Developer

Client: Verizon ∂

#### **Description:**

- Redesigned and improved the performance of Verizon's fault reporting system by 18% using Angular.
- Removed +2000 lines of repeated TypeScript code using the DRY principle.

#### IntelliSys D. Corp. ⊘

Software Developer

Nov 2020 - Aug 2021

Santiago de los Caballeros, Rep. Dom.

Client: Escuela Nacional de la Judicatura ₽

#### **Description:**

- Mentored 4 new appendices, front-end developers, in expanding web development skillset.
- Built a virtual library of Dominican jurisprudence optimized for academic and legal use which improved the experience of legal consultation by 13%.

Software Developer

Jul 2020 - Oct 2020

Santiago de los Caballeros, Rep. Dom.

Client: Consejo Nacional de Competitividad (CNC) ∂

#### **Description:**

• Developed user interfaces focused on telling the competitiveness history of the Dominican Republic with D3JS, HTML, and CSS, which improved user satisfaction by 31%.

Software Developer

Apr 2019 – Jun 2020

Santiago de los Caballeros, Rep. Dom.

Client: IntelliSys D. Corp. ∂

#### **Description:**

• Automated the internal processes of data collection and dashboard generation for the IntelliSys management team, using different micro-services created with NodeJS and Google Cloud Platform.

• Developed an application web with Node, React, and HTML/CSS that improved the efficiency of the administrative team in managing employee information by 15%

## **EDUCATION**

#### **BSc Computer Science**

Jan 2019 - Present

Universidad Tecnológica de Santiago (UTESA) ∂

### **Software Craftsman's Apprentice**

Jan 2018 - Aug 2019

Cincinnatus Institute of Craftsmanship, S.R.L. (CIC) ∂

IT Technician Aug 2014 – Jul 2018

Instituto Politécnico Industrial de Santiago (IPISA) ∂

# SKILLS

**Front-End** (React, Angular, Redux, TypeScript, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, and Material UI)

**Back-End** (Node.js, Express, PostgreSQL, SQL Server, Firebase, and GCP)

**Tools** (Git, GitHub, Postman, Figma, Bash, Jest, and Mocha)